Welcome!
欢迎你
In the last lecture, we implemented this can-climb-down check, and now we have the ability to tell
在上一讲中，我们实现了这个可以向下爬的检查，现在我们有能力来判断
whether or not we can climb down.
是否能爬下来。
The trace offset for these two line traces, we still need some tweaking in order for it
对于这两条线的轨迹偏移，我们仍然需要进行一些调整，以便让它
to work better, but before I do that, I'd like to get the animation ready first.
但在这之前，我想先把动画准备好。
So go back to my content browser, go inside of this animation, raw.
所以回到我的内容浏览器，进入这个动画的内部，原始。
So this is the animation that we need to adjust.
所以这是我们需要调整的动画。
Next, I'm going to double click to open it, and I'm going to select this root bone.
接下来，我将双击打开它，我将选择这个根骨。
The root bone here is not behaving the way we want.
这里的根骨的行为不是我们想要的。
Same as the last animation, we'll need to adjust this inside of Sequencer.
和上一个动画一样，我们需要在Sequencer中调整这个。
So I'm going to go back to my Control Rig and the map.
所以我将回到我的控制装备和地图。
So go back to my content folder, double click to open this map, then go back to raw, open
所以回到我的内容文件夹，双击打开这个地图，然后回到raw，打开这个动画，在Sequencer中点击编辑。
this animation, click edit in Sequencer, back to Control Rig, and click this button.
这个动画，在Sequencer中点击编辑，回到Control Rig，然后点击这个按钮。
Then go back to my viewport.
然后回到我的视口。
I'm going to delete this redundant track, and click play in here.
我将删除这个多余的轨道，然后点击这里的播放。
So this is the animation.
所以这就是动画了。
And same as the last one, all we need to do is to adjust this root control.
和上一个一样，我们需要做的就是调整这个根控制。
So first thing, I'm going to delete all of these existing keys, so select all of them,
所以第一件事，我要删除所有这些现有的键，所以选择所有的键、
then press delete.
然后按删除键。
And at the first frame, I'm going to move this root bone up to somewhere near here.
在第一帧，我将把这个根骨移到靠近这里的地方。
Alright, something like that.
好的，类似这样的东西。
Then click this button to add key.
然后点击这个按钮来添加钥匙。
So besides changing the location here, we also need to change its rotation in order
所以除了改变这里的位置，我们还需要改变它的旋转，以便
for our movement to match with this animation.
以使我们的运动与这个动画相匹配。
So I'm going to scroll forward a few frames to frame 22, and I'm going to move this root
所以我将向前滚动几帧到第22帧，然后我将把这个根
control forward, and I'm going to enable the snapping in here.
控件向前移动，并启用这里的抓取功能。
So rotate this root control in this direction.
所以把这个根控件朝这个方向旋转。
Alright, something like that.
好的，类似这样的东西。
Then click add key, and scroll back to preview this animation.
然后点击添加键，向后滚动以预览这个动画。
Alright, so far so good.
好了，到目前为止还不错。
Then I'm going to scroll forward a few more frames to somewhere near here, and select
然后我再向前滚动几帧，到这里附近的某个地方，然后选择
this root control.
这个根控件。
First I'm going to move it forward to somewhere near here, then move it down to here.
首先，我要把它向前移动到靠近这里的地方，然后向下移动到这里。
Then rotate it to something like this, and add keys.
然后把它旋转到像这样的地方，并添加按键。
Then about frame 41, I'm going to move this root control down.
然后在第41帧左右，我将把这个根控件向下移动。
I'm going to view it in different angles.
我要以不同的角度来观察它。
So drag it to here, then push it forward a little bit to somewhere near here, and move
所以把它拖到这里，然后把它往前推一点到这里附近的地方，然后把它往下移。
it down, then rotate it, then add keys.
它向下移动，然后旋转它，然后添加键。
And I'm going to forward a few more frames.
而我要再向前推几帧。
Then I think I want to move this root control down a little bit more.
然后我想我要把这个根控件再往下移一点。
So drag it down to something like this.
所以把它向下拖动到像这样的地方。
Alright, then click add keys, and I'm going to preview what I've just made.
好的，然后点击添加键，我将预览我刚刚做的东西。
So go back to the first frame, and try to see if this root control matches with this
所以回到第一帧，试试这个根控件是否与这个
animation.
动画。
Alright, I think this will work.
好的，我想这将会工作。
If it doesn't work, we can always come back to readjust it.
如果它不工作，我们可以随时回来重新调整。
And I'm going to right mouse button click this animation, then select this create linked
我准备用鼠标右键点击这个动画，然后选择创建链接的
animation sequence, place it inside of this animation folder, adjust it, rename it to
动画序列，把它放在这个动画文件夹里，调整它，把它改名为
climb down ledge underscore cr adjusted, then click OK.
climb down ledge underscore cr adjusted，然后点击OK。
Keep everything here at default, then click export.
保持这里的所有内容为默认，然后点击导出。
And go back to my content browser, I'm going to go to this adjust it folder, then double
回到我的内容浏览器，我将进入这个 "调整 "文件夹，然后双击打开这个 "爬下台阶"。
click to open this climb down ledge adjusted, and select this root bone.
点击打开这个 "爬下窗台调整"，并选择这个根骨。
So this is what we have.
所以这就是我们所拥有的。
And I'm going to try to enable the root motion in here.
我将尝试在这里启用根部运动。
Alright this should work.
好了，这应该可以了。
Later, when you are doing this yourself, this one is a bit more complicated than the last
稍后，当你自己做这个的时候，这个要比上一个复杂一点
one.
复杂一些。
Besides the location here, we also need to adjust its rotation.
除了这里的位置，我们还需要调整它的旋转。
And that shouldn't be something too difficult to do.
而这应该不是什么太难的事情。
So feel free to refer back to the video if you need help.
所以，如果你需要帮助，请随时参考视频。
And if you don't feel like going through this process, you can download the animation that
如果你不想经历这个过程，你可以下载这个动画。
I just adjusted in the resources drop down.
我只是在资源下拉菜单中进行了调整。
Now that we have the animation ready in the next lecture, we'll look at how we can actually
现在我们已经准备好了动画，在下一讲中，我们将看看我们如何能够实际地
use it.
使用它。
I'll see you in the next lecture.
下一讲见。
[Music]
[音乐]